Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Hello. Good evening. Good day everybody
and welcome to the 260th episode of the
Ask Abijit show. Hope everybody is doing
great. Uh let us see who all is there on
the live chat. I can see Amish Mishra
Gores KB geopolitical the way from indor
Yashtiagi Somi join event countdown the
Bharat Emperor Kumar Kaneska Spade
Vidiar
U Sumit Agarwal Trip Mishra Rashab Yadav
who says it is not live. If it is not
live, how is this happening sir? Uh yeah
and xenomorphosis Rajat Duhan Rohit
Janged Hitan Shua Sama Tripati Unknown
Kartik Da Shivas Sai Alvin Rodriguez
Dhiraj Kamat Nanda Kizor NTN88 Sonia
Siddha Spade Mystic SK Dir Kamat uh
Sharma Nikil Vak Rahul Dunak Kumar
Kanesh Kala Chakram Smokey Abhishek S
who is a new member welcome Thank thank
you so much for becoming becoming a
member. Dr. Ritwick Patnay uh Yami
Manisha Matei Sumit Agarwal Sarang
Dinale Lone Walker Duv Durya Abin Achara
Prrenay Panic Shai Sasank Ashwani Yraj
Ashish Pandel Abishek P info Edge Rashmi
Ratur Tas
anonymous Mr. Ben Salman, Dipti
Designer, Yesh Abijit M, Sh Mishra,
Uchiha Whiti, Kapalin, Kyad, Chad,
Chetan, Naradia, Bai, Ruchika, Pal and
so many so many other people. Vikash PJ,
Mlovin, Anonymous Scientist, Priyanka,
Jawalia, Hunter, Canv. Okay, okay, okay.
Thank you so much for all of you to all
of you for being on the live chat on the
live stream. Let's take some questions.
What questions do we have? The scrummer
says the what are my views on the
British F-35 being easily detected.
So the Indian u um authorities put out a
tweet I believe I think the Indian Navy
put out a tweet where saying that the uh
British F-35 was detected and brought in
for processing or something like that.
Well um I don't know. So I've always
maintained that it's not the best
aircraft in the world. It doesn't mean
it's a terrible aircraft but u so maybe
it's detectable by the by the Indian um
detection systems
maybe it is looks like it is right so if
it is so then I would say my view is
that it's I'm glad that it was easily
detected by India so what happened is
that this aircraft there was this
aircraft carrier British aircraft
carrier that is currently operating
somewhere in the western Indian Ocean
also allegedly called the Arabian Sea
And uh it one of the F-35s was trying to
land on the aircraft carrier in in bad
weather, a lot of rainfall and all. It
they made multiple passes but was unable
to land. It was running short of fuel.
So it had to then move to and and seek
uh a landing in Thirwan and Tapam
and we allowed the aircraft to land and
we refueled it and we may have sent it
back on its way eventually possibly. So
that's what happened and it looks like
we were able to detect it pretty easily.
So nice nice. What about your stealth?
Ashish says, "Dr. and I Delhi
demonstrate quantum entanglement based
free space quantum secure communication
over more than 1 kilometer distance.
What does this mean?"
So um okay
demonstrate quantum entanglement based
free space quantum secure communication.
Quantum entanglementbased quantum
communications.
So quantum entanglement is a property
quantum mechanical property where if you
have a pair of entangled particles which
means that they are both described by
the same wave function then if you have
access to one particle and you know its
state and properties then you will
immediately know the state of the other
particle as well instantaneously. No
matter how near or far it is, even if it
is a 100 light years away, you'll
immediately know some aspects of its
properties. That's that's quantum
entanglement. And this can allow you to
have very secure communications that
this is the basis of a set of new
emerging technologies, communication
technologies. And maybe you can uh it
can
it can be super secure and uh nobody can
snoop in, snoop on it on so on so forth,
that sort of thing. So uh and the
Chinese have been at the forefront of
this technology. They had launched a
satellite called Mishius I believe a few
years ago
and they were able to u have
communications between the satellite and
a ground station over several hundred
kilometers in real time or something
like that using they were able to
entangle particles between the satellite
and and a ground station. Um so India is
now beginning to looks like based on
this news this piece of news that you're
telling me looks like India is making
some kind of progress in this so I think
it's good uh India obviously needs to
ensure it doesn't get left behind when
it comes to quantum technologies and so
on. So um quantum entanglement based
secure communication is essentially if
you do it right it is it is nobody can
hack it. It is super encrypted and so
on. uh nobody can break the encryption
that's what one hears I have not really
looked into it but yeah so if if if this
is the this is true this news report
then it's good progress for India in
that direction
Kaneshka says Mr. Gandhi justified Brits
for Jalan Wala bag massacre what can be
the reason for justification can you
discuss his actual statement why I I am
not an expert in Mr. Gandhi Mr. Gandhi
is not somebody who interests me
tremendously. Uh I don't know if he
justified the the the Jillian Bala bag
massacre or not, but clearly he had a
very lenient perspective on what the
British did. Uh I'm not sure if he
actually uh supported the massacre, but
I don't think he rallied the nation to
stand up against the British and depose
the British for what they had done that
he did not. Uh so I don't know if he did
any justification. Okay. I don't know
his actual statements. I am not aware of
it but one does know that Mr. Gandhi had
a very lenient approach towards the
British and lots of people will be
unhappy when I say that but look
did he ever ask the Indian armed forces
to take up weapons against the British
that would have solved the problem of
foreign occupation in 24 hours but he
did not do that so
there we have it
God says if there was no cast discrimin
look I don't discuss cast I don't
discuss all these matters okay And I
have no no idea about the bakti movement
and all that stuff. I I have not studied
these matters and I have no interest in
these these these issues that the
British created of cast discrimination
and then they're blaming us for all
this. Whatever problems existed in
Indian society during foreign
occupation, you cannot blame Indian
society for those problems.
Okay, let me address this.
Steve Jobs was at the head.
He's the founder, right? Steve Jobs of
Apple. Then Steve Jobs was thrown out of
his company,
right? Steve Jobs was thrown out of his
of the company he founded.
And then over the next few years, Apple
as a as a company nearly went bankrupt
and then Steve Jobs has had to come back
into Apple and he was able to save Apple
and create and transform it into the
behemoth that it is today. Now this
intervening period between the time that
Steve Jobs is thrown out of the company
and the time that the company nearly
goes bankrupt,
Apple did terribly right those years.
Who will you blame for Apple's
performance? Will you blame the
employees or will you blame the people
who are in charge of making decisions?
Will you blame the people who are in
control of the company and deciding what
happens in the company or will you blame
the employees?
Now during the time that India was under
foreign occupation, India's society was
not allowed to function the way it was
supposed to function. It was not allowed
to function the way it had evolved to
function for thousands of years.
During foreign occupation, India society
was under a tremendous amount of stress
and pressure. There was an ongoing
genocide, cultural genocide, endemic
genocide that was going on. So all kinds
of
malpractices crept into Indian society.
You you people must have seen Harry
Potter. Some of you must have seen it.
In Harry Potter, there's a cast system,
right? Four houses.
In Hogwarts, there are four houses.
That's Slytherin, Hufflepuff, Ramenclaw,
and Gryffindor. Four houses. And there's
a sorting hat that decides what is each
student's aptitude and which house are
they best suited for. Now imagine a
situation in which Voldemort wins and he
destroys the sorting hat and he says
that only Slytherin is the best and
everybody else is evil and he decides he
says that go henceforth you can no
longer determine what house you can go
into based on your aptitudes. You can
only determine what house you can go
into based on the house that your
parents were in.
then it becomes solidified and oified in
that manner because of the evil guy
Voldemort. Right? Because the the
Hogwarts society is no longer able to
function the way it was supposed to
function.
So this is what happened in Indian
society. We were under foreign
occupation. We were under tremendous
oppression. We were under we were
undergoing genocide
and all kinds of bad things crept into
Indian society slowly slowly gradually
over time over hundreds of years
and then the British come and write that
it was all cast discrimination and then
Indians who were brainwashed into
believing all this by the textbooks by
their teachers by the professors they
will come and ask me these questions.
So this is something that I have zero
interest in. Okay. And Indian society
was the best society in the world. The
most the nicest society in the world.
Least amount of discrimination or
whatever. I mean if you compare to other
societies, you you haven't studied other
societies in the world. You haven't
studied Greek society. You haven't
studied Roman society. You haven't
studied studied Chinese society. You
haven't studied medieval or or other
kinds of English society, French
society. You haven't done that. But all
you want to do is blame your own people
and your own ancestors.
This is so annoying and I've had enough
of this. Seriously,
Kumar can. Okay, we took this question.
We took this question, didn't we?
Okay. P info says
this is not a question about geopolitic
history or or current affairs. Anyhow,
since you have asked it, I will take one
question like this and no more. done in
done bachelor's and masters in computer
science. Got a good job on campus for
after a few months. I left it for UPSC
preparations and wested five years. I'm
seriously worried about the future.
Should I upskill? Get back into it.
Advice. You should get back into
whatever you good at.
See, things happen. Okay? Things happen.
Sometimes you make bad choices in life.
Everybody makes bad choices in life.
You're not the only one. You made a
mistake. Maybe maybe some wiser older
people told you to do this or or
whatever whichever way it happened.
Okay, now you are where you are. There's
no point crying about the past. At least
you can learn from the past. Now you
have to ask yourself what am I good at?
What are what what what are the skills
that I already have and what are the
what are the aptitudes that I have?
Which means that what kind of skills can
I pick up very fast quickly. If you are
good at it, do upskill and get back into
it. Otherwise find something else that
you're good at and get into that. But uh
yeah, after after five years have gone
down the the bridge gone go that much
time has gone. I think you need to get
serious and quickly make a decision as
to what you want to do, what you're good
at. If you need to upskill, upskill. If
you if you think you're great at it,
then you should get back into it and and
so on. So the the point is that unless I
know you personally, I really cannot
answer you. I can't really give you
advice because I don't know you
personally. I don't know what you're
good at. I don't know what your
strengths and weaknesses are. I don't
know what your background is. So, I
really can't answer you, you know,
properly. But I would say you have to
introspect and find out whatever it is
that you are great at and you need to
double down on that and make that your
career. Okay, sir. All the best.
Pan Shri Hasha says, "Pranam G, if the
League of Nations failed because of
World War II, how come the UN is still
functioning because of despite numerous
wars? Does it show US clout?" The UN is
functioning, my dear friends, because it
serves the interests of the dominant
forces and powers in the world today.
The UN doesn't do a thing for the world.
It's just a huge sponge that absorbs
money from from all its member states.
Everybody pays it some money. Then the
vast majority of the money that is paid
to the UN is burnt up
to pay the salaries
and business class trips and fivestar
hotel stays of its employees of its top
employees
and the UN doesn't do a thing. There are
all kinds of conflicts happening in the
world. Does the Ukraine conflict going
on? What has What has the UN done to
stop this conflict? Absolutely nothing.
There's the Middle East crisis that's
going on. It's now a flame. What has the
UN done? Absolutely nothing. Toothless,
useless organization. There's a
tremendous humanitarian situation right
now in Sudan.
What is the UN doing? Nothing. So the UN
exists
to further the geopolitical interests of
the of the two or three nations that
really control it. Maybe two two nations
that control it. Historically it's been
the US and the USSR who were the major u
nations that control it. Then the US had
a had a uniolar moment for 20 plus years
in which it was the only nation that
controlled the UN. Now China has made
inroads into the UN. it has infiltrated
deep into the UN and it uses the UN to
further the Chinese geopolitical agenda
as best as it can. So the UN is still
functioning because it has some value
for the US and China and whoever else
has some kind of you know has the
knowhow of how to use these multi
multilateral organizations to suit their
geopol to serve their geopolitical
interests. That's why the UN continues
and these nations will not allow the UN
to be dissolved. They will as long as
possible keep the UN going in the
current shape and form. The UN is a
snapshot of the world as it was in 1945.
It's completely terribly obsolete,
outdated, useless organization, but they
will keep it going as long as they can.
Okay.
Pman Shrihar says is gender surgery deep
state tool. It very well could be. It's
absolutely
unnatural, isn't it?
And uh yeah, it it could be. Yes.
Is the series Europa the last whatever
uh Europa the last war factual or not?
Well, if I had seen it, I would be able
to answer it. I haven't seen it.
Dr. Redu Padnag says, "What if Iran lost
and an American puppet state is
established in Iran? What will happen to
Chabahar portur impact of Iran and
Pakistan on India? See currently you
have a government in Iran which is the
government of the moolas and the ayatas
right I mean you have a president and
all but the president is not the all
powerful person in the country it is
ayatah Mr. Kabani who is the supreme
leader the president simply serves him
president doesn't have the power the
kind of power Mr.
has. So, Iran is a government of the
moolas and the Ayatas. Okay? It's an
Islamic government. It's Shia. It's a
Shia country.
Now, that's the country that is now at
war with Israel. Israel started it all,
you could say, right? By launching
strikes, decapitation strikes on the
Iranian government, higher authorities,
higher leadership, as well as nuclear
sites and military installations. and
Iran has been forced to retaliate. Now
let's say there's a regime change in
Iran in Thran. The current government is
overthrown and a democratic government
comes to power. H what does it mean that
a democratic democratic government comes
to power? It means a pro- US government
comes to power.
So then what happens? What what will
happen then? Well, all you have to ask
yourself is what happened when there was
a the last time there was a pro- US
government in Iran. That was the regime
of the Shah Shah Muhammad the Razabi.
He was a US puppet. He was very strongly
pro- US. Thran was a US vasal at the
time. And in 1965 when India and
Pakistan went to war, they supported
Pakistan.
They supported Pakistan not just in
words but in actions.
They allowed Pakistan to fly their
fighter aircraft aircraft and land those
aircraft in on Iranian air bases so that
India would not destroy them and so on
and so forth. They supported Pakistan.
So if today a pro- US
democratic government comes to power in
Iran, what will happen is that you will
have two Pakistans to your west. not
just west Pakistan but also Iran which
will be pro- US. So we will lose
whatever access we have to Chabahar port
or maybe it will it will continue to
exist in name but for all means and
purposes for all intents and purposes uh
we will not really be able to use it
much. Okay. So this will also affect the
Balojasthan liberation movement which
which will be crushed from Iran
and and so on.
So this will be a tremendous setback for
India.
We have reasonably good relations with
the government in Thran today. If a US
of if if a pro- US government comes to
power in Thran, it will be a big setback
for us. They will be anti-India just
like the Muhammad Yunus regime is
anti-India. So East Pakistan, West
Pakistan, the way they are anti-India,
even Thran will be anti-India. And this
is what these Indian geopolitical
analysts don't understand.
There are very intelligent Indian
geopolitical analysts who are all
supporting the US and Iraq Israel u war
on the seem to not understand what the
repercussions of this will be. If
there's a regime change in Thran, it'll
be terrible for India. India will be
isolated in the region. We have been
talking about isolated Pakistan. We will
become isolated in the region.
Russia will face a setback. China will
also face a setback but they'll they'll
manage. So it will be terrible for India
if this happens.
Abishek welcome to the membership and
thank you so much for becoming a member.
Sharma says India Indians mostly eat
carbs like rice, rice, lentils and wheat
very little meat or eggs yet our health
is declining. On average we getting
shorter. So why is there still an
obsession with being pure wage? It's
because of cultural and civilizational
reasons. Our culture has always uh
regarded uh nonviolence as the ideal
ideal state of being. So as far as
possible don't indulge in cruelty even
by proxy and uh don't harm any living
being. That's been the ideal. So that's
the ideal state of existence for for a
person who follows dharma. Of course we
have had exceptions in this. I mean
kings and warriors the people of the
warrior class they would they would
usually uh eat meat and you know it
depends on the occupation you would
have. So if you are a warrior or if
you're somebody who is into heavy
physical labor you would typically
historically Indians of of of who
engaged in those professions would have
eaten meat no question about that. So
the khatrias would have eaten meat and
the people who engage in heavy physical
labor would eat meat and in some parts
of India certain kinds of meat are not
regarded as meat. For example in Bengal
they regard fish as being vegetarian and
so on. But if you look at overall India
today like you're saying Sharma Mr.
Sharma yes Indians eat what's what I I
call a starvation diet. So the British
occupied India for two and a half
centuries and they systematically
starved India by imposing by unleashing
famine after famine artificial famine
after artificial famine on India because
of it because of which Indians had to
really change and modify their diet to
to what do you call a starvation diet
just to somehow barely survive. So it
was all based heavily on carbohydrates
and this messed up the Indian genetics
and and much more. Indians have a much
higher prevalence of diabetes for
example than the rest of the world uh
because of the the consequences of two
and a half centuries of artificially
engineered starvation by the British. So
today Indians think that this starvation
diet that we've had to follow for two
and a half centuries it is our
tradition. So we our diets starting from
morning breakfast it's all carbs carbs
carbs idlies and dosas and whatnot.
Otherwise it is what puffed rice pas and
and potato based stuff and all. So you
start from the morning breakfast full of
carbs. Your lunch is full of carbs. Your
dinner is full of carbs. Your snacks are
full of carbs and sugar and that's it.
Most Indians don't eat any protein. And
some Indians are are they labor under
the delusion that dals and lentils and
all they will give you sufficient
protein. They will give you sufficient
protein but they will give you an
overload of carbs along with the
sufficient protein. So if you want 100 g
grams of protein, so let's say you get
it from paneer, it comes with certain
amount of calories and fats. But if you
want 100 grams of protein from let's say
pink dal or something, you will get a
tremendous carb dose with that.
You there's no way of getting clean
low-fat low carb protein without being a
non-vegetarian. So that's the dilemma
that vegetarians face. What to do about
it? We are vegetarian. We don't want to
um you know uh cause any harm, any pain,
any suffering to to living beings. So we
have decided to be vegetarian. Now what
do we do now? Well, that's a question I
can't answer. If you really want clean,
lean protein without an overload of
carbohydrates, the only way you do it is
either by going down the route of paneer
which has a lot of fat or by eating
meat. That's the solution. There is no
other clean solution. You can get your
150 grams of protein if you want per day
as a vegetarian, but you will get a
tremendous overload of carbs with that.
That's the deal.
Okay. NTN88 says, "How tangible is
bricks?" Tangible. Tangible. How
tangible is bricks? What is my opinion
on bricks currency? Is multipolar India
hurdle to this currency? How tangible?
I'm not sure what you mean by tangible.
Tangible means something you can touch.
So, you see this thing here? I can touch
it. This is tangible. This tangible.
Tangible. See? Tangible. I can touch it.
That's what the what what the word
tangible means. Bricks
is an economic
um coalition of nations. It's not
something you can touch. It's not
tangible.
Right? Just like the EU is not tangible
or NATO is not tangible or the UN is not
tangible. It has buildings and all but
it's an abstract idea, isn't it? So, I
don't know what what what do you mean by
tangible? Uh, but how
how seriously should should we take
bricks? How viable is bricks? If that's
what you're asking, how how impactful
can bricks be? If that's what you're
asking, it will have a moderate impact
because it is not an alliance. It is a
coalition.
It's not an official alliance that is
treaty based in which we have very clear
uh clauses and proper charters of what
what the alliance entails. There's none
of that. So it's an alliance of
convenience. It's an economic it's it's
it's a coalition of convenience. It's a
coalition, economic coalition and uh
there is no common currency and a nation
like India will not want a common
currency because see otherwise what
happens is like what happened in the EU
in the EU you have a current common
currency the the the euro which is
nothing but a
a proxy for the Deutsche mark. So it's
Germany that's taken over Europe through
the e through through through the euro
which is nothing but a continuation in a
different name of the deutsche mark. Now
if you have a bricks currency it will be
dominated by China not even by Russia
right because India is the larger
economy compared to Russia but China is
way bigger than India. So China will
dominate the bricks currency and they
will control be the controlling factor
behind it. India will never want that.
India will never allow that. So if if
there's a proposal for a bricks
currency, India will say we're not
participating in that and that kills the
whole matter. Right? So India is not a
multipolar nation. India is a
multi-aligned nation and India has its
own very strong interests and we are
unwilling to subordinate our interests
to those of China and that's why a
bricks currency is not going to happen.
So I hope I answered your questions sir.
Shubam Dubet says um what are the
current scientific possibilities for
uncovering and understanding
multi-dimensional reality within the
universe? Begin exploring them. What are
the current scientific
possibilities
for uncovering and understanding
multi-dimensional reality? Well, first
of all, you have to ask yourself, does
the universe have a multi-dimensional
reality? We are aware of of four
dimensions.
length, breadth, height. Yeah. Length,
breadth, height, you know,
and time. These are the four dimensions
we can visualize, we can see, experience
either directly or somewhat vaguely.
Time is somewhat vague. But we do
experience the passage of time. So we
have four dimensions that we are
familiar with. Three are very concrete,
one is kind of vague. We we experience
its passage. Do we have more dimensions?
Do we have evidence of a fifth
dimension, sixth dimension, 10
dimensions, 11 dimensions, 26
dimensions? Do we have evidence of that?
Zero. Absolutely zero evidence of that.
So first, if you want to uncover and
understand multi-dimensional reality,
you have to find evidence for at least
one more dimension and that currently
doesn't exist. How would you find the
evidence for an extra dimension for
let's say a fifth dimension as in the
kuda client theory for example? Well,
one of the possibilities is that if
there if there are more dimensions,
those are super compactifified
dimensions, extremely small curled up
such that and so small that we can't
experience them. So for that we would
need to be to to to uncover if such
dimensions if they potentially exist.
You would need to uh be able to explore
the ultra microscopic world and we have
limitations in that. uh we have electron
microscopes and we have various probes
that we can use to to to probe the the
world at the quantum scale but even at
the quantum scale we haven't uncovered
any existence or of extra dimensions. Um
we have even been able to do deep
inelastic deep inelastic scattering
which is the probing of of the the the
internal structure of of nucleons partn
and and still we haven't uncovered extra
dimensions. So as far as we know there
are no extra dimensions. The
multi-dimensional blah blah blah that
that is spoken about is spoken about by
string theorists.
So in string theory first of all we have
something called kaluda kind theory
which was proposed in the 1920s30s and
it was a significant theoretical
breakthrough of of some kind in uh in
kind of attempted to unify gravity with
electromagnetism. Yeah. Uh and then
string theory talks about 10 dimensional
spa sp space sp space sp space sp space
sp space sp space sp space sp space sp
space sp space time 11 dimensional
spacetime bzonic string theory talks
about 26 dimensions and all that but
where's the evidence? Zero.
So, how do you possibly find new
dimensions? By by probing the ultra
microscopic world, the quantum domain
even deeper. But that's really really
really difficult because you need
extremely high energy to do that. And
the highest energies we have as of now
are found in the heart of the large
Hadron Collider in Geneva, Switzerland.
And that's not given us any
breakthroughs in this direction. All
right, sir. Nandanda Kizor says no
question. Oh well thank you so much.
Thank you so much. Very nice of you.
Appreciate it.
Goinda says do you think the US will
give F22 Raptor to Israel? Not even to
Israel. I doubt it. That's not to be
given to anybody. Not even to Israel.
Rashi Gudin says, "How did you start
this YouTube channel and grow audience?"
Look, that's not a question about
geopolitic history and or current
affairs. It's a historical question but
it's just four years four year old
history. I started the channel because I
had something to say. I thought let's
say something and then it turned out
that people wanted to hear what I had to
say
and uh so I continued and that's how it
happened and the audience grew itself.
Okay. Rahul says given recent events can
we now say that the cold war never ended
was only paused and it's now back in
full swing. No. The cold war ended with
a US victory. The 20th century cold war
ended properly. It ended with a US
victory. It ended with the dissolution,
permanent dissolution of the USSR, which
was a comprehensive US political victory
without the need for military force.
That was a definitive end to the cold
war. That happened in what 1990, let's
say 1991.
And it went on this this state of
affairs this uniolar state of affairs
went on until the year 2007208
which is what
which is at least about about 20 years
which is about 20 years roughly. So you
had a roughly 20 year period
and and China started showing its its
true face around 2012.
So you had a roughly 20 21 year period
in which there was just one superpower
the US the sole superpower and there was
no cold war for 20 years because the the
reason for the cold war was gone. Russia
was in on its knees and the new cold war
the one we are in now has just started
recently. It the first seeds the first
uh the ev the first evidence of that was
visible during Trump's first presidency.
uh it's it it uh it continued during
Biden Biden's presidency and now we are
seeing a full-blown cold war. So this is
cold war 2.0. It's not a continuation of
the old cold war. This is this is the
new cold war. And over here the dominant
actor is the US and it's aimed primarily
at China and secondarily at Russia and
whoever else.
Goen says, "How do you think the US will
contain the situation after Iran
potentially tests a nuclear weapon?"
All you have to ask yourself is how has
the US responded to something like this
in the past?
So when did we have something like this
in the past? It's when North Korea
tested nuclear weapons.
How did the US respond?
Nothing much. imposition of sanctions
but no military action.
Right?
So if Iran tests a nuclear weapon, I
would expect that there will be the
imposition of all kinds of sanctions on
Iran beyond what you already have
and that would be about it. It will be
very dangerous to to take any military
action against a nation that has nuclear
weapons and also has tremendously good
ballistic missiles.
Right. So it would definitely cause Iran
to be isolated globally. Uh it may also
come under pressure from its own allies
the which is China and Russia. Possibly
at least lip service pressure will be
imposed by Russia and China
and it would impact Russia more than
China because it would open up a new
nuclear front for Russia actually. So
Russia will not be very pleased. But uh
if Iran feels that it has no choice then
it may test a nuclear weapon and what
would the US do? I think it will impose
sanctions. Beyond that, it can't do much
more. In my opinion, it's very
dangerous. It's very ill advised to
launch a nuclear to to launch a military
operation on a nuclear power with the
proven ability to deliver warheads and
to puncture the iron dome. Oh,
absolutely. You can't you can't mess
with that.
Vijay says, "Why did Buddhism lose to
Hinduism of the subcontinent?" That's a
long long history. It changes things
change. There was a time when jinism was
the dominant was a very dominant uh
dharmic path in in the subcontinent.
Eventually things changed. I think one
of the reasons one of the major reasons
is the life and career of Adish
Shankarachara. He did a lot to revive uh
the older the older uh
schools of thought vidanta etc.
So I think it was one man who who
brought brought what we call Hinduism
back. Even the Buddh Buddhism, Hinduism
it's all part of the same Dharmic
umbrella but different worldviews,
slightly different worldviews and
slightly different philosophical
outlooks. So it's because of I would say
Adishankaria that this transformation
happened.
Uh Goin says what's the new method of
strikes that Iran is claiming it used
for strikes against Israel? new method
of strikes. Is there one? Um they've
used what Iran has done is that they've
used uh saturation attacks on Israel. A
saturation attack is a ma it gives you a
mathematical certainty of hitting some
targets. So let's say so we know that
Israel has this uh aerial defense system
called the iron dome system, right? Very
expensive arrow rockets and whatever
else rockets that are used to target
incoming threats.
Now, let's say the Iron Dome system is a
thousand
missiles, defensive missiles. So, all
you have to do is to launch 10, 101
missiles at the Iron Dome, and there's a
guarantee that at least one missile will
hit its target. And of course, the the
interception accuracy is never 100%. So,
you will have more missiles that will
hit the targets. And the Iron Dome
obviously will not all be used at the
same time. So you can use strike
packages of let's say 100 missiles at a
time at a city and then there's almost
100% guarantee that a few of them will
slip through. So I think what is Iran is
doing it's using um saturation strikes
on on on Israel and what it is also
doing is that you know it's using a lot
of its old slowmoving ballistic missiles
but slipping in in a few hypersonics in
between which is why the hypersonics you
can clearly see the difference in their
speed and all that and they're able to
get through the defenses. So that's
that's what Iran has been doing the past
3 four days.
Zishan says, "Do you think Israel will
be able to get the US involved in the
Iran war? Have you seen General Wesley
Clark video of invading seven
countries?" Yeah, with Iran being the
last Netanyahu openly stated his
intentions on Fox News.
I have seen that that video from 2007 or
wherever it was that the US had a had a
hit list of seven countries that would
be invaded. Just because we can, we'll
do it. And Iran is one of those. Iran
may be the last of those. The question
is, will Israel be able to get invol get
the US involved in this war?
Well, I'm sure there are various ways of
getting the US involved in the war.
Okay, I will not utter those words here
because those are nasty ways. But yeah,
Israel, if it wants, it can get
involved. It can get the US involved in
the war. Um, see, one of the best ways
to do it is to do a false flag
operation. Okay, this is all
theoretical. I'm not saying anybody's
planning to do it. I'm saying
theoretically, theoretically, completely
hypothetically, completely fictitious
scenario. Let's say I want to get my
ally involved in the war. So, I will
launch a false flag attack on my allies
warship and claim it was done by the
other guy and that's how the ally gets
involved in the war. So that is one
completely hypothetical fictitious
scenario in which you can plausibly get
your ally involved in the war even
though the ally was per may perhaps have
been reluctant to get involved
and once something starts it's very hard
to stop it right the fog of war takes
over likelvitz
would have said
um so yeah we are in a very dangerous
situation right now
multiple actors all want different
things. The question is what does each
each actor want? What does Iran want?
What does Israel want? What does the US
want?
Does the US actually want the
destruction of Iran and a regime change?
And at what cost? If yes, the question
also is what does Israel want? Does it
want a permanent end to the regime in in
Thran, a regime change before Iran goes
nuclear? And what's the cost it's it's
willing to absorb for this to happen?
and is it willing to drag its ally into
the war through various means and so on.
So I think it's possible if Iran if
Israel if Israel really wants to get the
US involved in this war that would be a
major conflration in which you have a
major regional war involving multiple
actors
beyond Iran, Israel and the US multiple
actors will be involved in that case.
Okay, Jay Tiwari says, "What if Pakistan
collapses? Is India ready?" India is
ready. All you have to do is to seal the
border. That's it. Somebody come tries
to come this side, deal with them.
That's all you have to do. Beyond that,
nothing will happen. I'll tell you why
nothing will happen. The big worry that
people have is what about those nuclear
weapons?
Do we want those nuclear weapons falling
into the hands of unwanted people?
They're already in the hands of unwanted
people. They're already in the hands of
terrorists.
The question is what happens if the
Pakistani military regime falls? What
happens? Don't worry, the US will take
care of it. Those nuclear weapons belong
to the US. Those are not Pakistani
nuclear weapons. Those are weapons the
US has placed on Pakistan soil to deal
with
to to counterbalance India as well as
potentially China and Iran, but mainly
India. So if the Pakistan regime
collapses, the Americans will do a
mop-up operation very rapidly. They are
already in control of the Nurhan air
base, Pakistani officers and personnel
are not allowed there. So it's very
clear that these nuclear weapons that
Pakistan supposedly has are American
nuclear weapons. In 1998 after India
tested five nuclear weapons, how was
Pakistan able to so quickly on demand
test five or whatever nuclear weapons?
because they were ready because those
were American nuclear weapons and the
Americans facilitated those so-called
tests.
So we didn't we did not worry about the
nuclear threat and if Pakistan collapses
all we have to do is to secure our
borders that's all and maybe do
something more beyond that. That's up to
the government of India.
Vishal says do you think Iran may have
lost the capacity to capability to
enrich uranium further after Israeli
strikes? I doubt it. Some of it may have
been affected but not all of it.
So the Iranians did hit the Natans side,
the fu furus side and so on. But I think
that's not all, right? I think Iran
still has more capability to enrich
uranium. So I don't think Iran Iran has
lost all of its capability to enrich
uranium. I think they will now double
down on enriching uranium beyond 60%.
I think in in the next 3 months they may
have a sufficiently reasonably large
stockpile of 90% plus enriched uranium.
It makes sense for them to have it if
they feel that there is an existential
threat to their nation which there
probably is. So I think they'll be able
to do it.
Spade says Indian army parade versus US
Army parade.
Yes, we all saw that. We all saw Trump's
birthday military parade. It was an
embarrassment. It was seriously an
embarrassment. Sad to see that.
He was expecting something like what
what Kim Jong-un would have. But what
ended up was something very different.
What he ended up having was something
very different. Very embarrassing.
Uh Ritik Patnak says, "Dr. Ritik Patnag,
why is Russia not that powerful today
like before? It's because of the past 30
years of history. Whatever happened
since 1991
u you know Russia was was beggared by
Boris Yelin. It was sold off peace meal
meal to a bunch of oligarchs who
proceeded to deliberately destroy the
Russian economy and the Russian
industrial capacity and Putin had to
rebuild it step by step brick by brick
over decades and he's still in the
process of doing it. That's why
project smiling Buddha I heard
right-wing YouTubers going gaga over
F-35. I wonder who those gentlemen and
ladies are. They say it is technically
so superior that we can ignore all other
aspects like kill switch etc. I would
look I don't know who who these
right-wing YouTubers could or could not
be. Okay, I'm not aware of these people.
I'm just saying that if these uh highly
learned people are saying the F-35 is
fantastic, one would want to look into
the sources the the sources of their
income. What are the income streams?
Who's who's paying them to say this?
Okay,
the F-35 is dangerous. It is a if we
acquire it, it will be a huger liability
than the Starlink. Okay, the F-35 will
kill will come with kill switches. It
will come with spyware. It will come
with back doors. It will completely
compromise India's national security.
And when we will need it, when the hour
will come, when we actually need it, it
won't
perform.
Especially if it goes against, if it
goes counter to American interests,
we should not acquire this flying trash
can, the F-35. And if some YouTubers are
saying we should, then I hardly question
why they are saying this and who is
paying them to say this. I'm talking
about YouTubers, whoever they may be.
Okay? I don't know who is saying this or
who is not saying it. I'm just saying
big question mark about about these
people. So either they are seriously
deficient in their analysis or they are
motivated by something beyond
their intellect which could be financial
motivations possibly.
Feminist Slayer says just like strong
nations prepare for war or sanctions
even during peaceful times should
individuals also prepare for personal
crisis during good times. Absolutely.
Absolutely. How do you do that? By by
investing in savings and by having Yeah,
it's see what you do as an individual.
You can't obviously build an army. You
can't have nuclear weapons and so on.
But what you can do is you can have a
finan strong finances. So during peace
time when everything is fine, save
money, invest money wisely, make your
money work for you and have different
forms of investment. Some of it could be
let's say in real estate. Some of it
could be in stocks and bonds and shares.
Some of it could be in precious metals.
Some of it could be in something else
and so on and so forth. So that if if
someday something goes wrong, you have
multiple recourses and you know you're
financially fine to tide over whatever
bad times and however long they may
last. So yes, you can learn a lot from
the study of geopolitics in personal
life.
Anonymous scientist says, "How would
India have been today if Neu had
accepted Kennedy's offer to help India
detonate a nuclear device and join the
UN Security Council?" Well, you could
have it would have gone two ways or
maybe three ways. First, India could
have become a complete US vasal if uh
the leader would have been less than
sufficiently intelligent, right?
Complete US vasal. So, imagine a larger
Pakistan in some way. Maybe India could
have been like that and then India could
have been crippled the way Japan has
been crippled today or South Korea. So
India's population would have been
prosperous but India's national national
interest national national security etc
would have gone to the docks complete US
vasal a nation that exists only to serve
the master that could have happened or
if we had a sufficiently intelligent
leader bright leader with a makyavian
chanakian mindset then we would have
balanced the whole world against each
other and we would have used this to our
advantage we would have become a nuclear
weapons power. We would have m
maintained sufficient
friendship but not too much friendship
with the US.
We would never have become a proper
ally. We would have kept them at an arms
distance but also kept them sufficiently
close so that they feel like you know
their investment is good while also
being multi-aligned with the rest of the
world. We would have welcomed US
investment and so on the way China did
for example, right?
So it it would have depended on the kind
of leadership we had and obviously if
Mr. Neu had been the leader it would
have gone in a in a specific way which
uh I suppose people can think about and
I will not need to spell it out.
Priya Bhadwaj says, "How to counter the
Chinese electronics market? M
Semiconductor Btech E. How to start my
own manufacturing in India. Run my own
tech blog greatly.
How to counter the Chinese electronics
market? Well, we need to to have our own
research and development. We need to
have we need to develop our own
technologies. We need to do it
uh if required from scratch. we need to
do it by possibly having the west invest
in India and transfer some technology
that we can then build upon. Uh there's
a multiplicity of ways in which to do it
but it needs to be done and and the
question you to ask yourself is how did
the Chinese build up their electronics
uh manufacturing capability?
There was a time where they had zero
electronics manufacturing capability.
How did they do it? So by studying how
the Chinese did it and by adop adapting
that to a certain extent because it
won't work exactly the way it worked
then for them it won't work the same way
for us we'll have to do it somewhat
differently because today the west
doesn't want India to rise like the next
China so they will be very wary of
sharing technology
certain kinds of technology and so on so
we'll have to do it differently but we
can certainly take the Chinese model as
an example of how things are done and we
can adapt that to our circumstances.
Now, how do you want to how to start
your own manufacturing in India? First
of all, you need investment. You need
somebody to fund you. In case you have
deep pockets, well, then you can take
the risk and use some of your own
funding. Otherwise, you need to be able
to attract the right kind of investment.
For that, you have to show the right
business plan and show that you have the
the knowhow and so on so forth to make
it work and so on. And then you have to
acquire land and set up the
manufacturing plant and somehow make it
profitable while also navigating the red
tape and the business environment in
India. It's pretty difficult but people
can do it. Many people are doing it. So
yeah that's kind of how it works.
Um and if if that's something you're
considering seriously then I would wish
you all the best sir.
Echo says why is veto power crucial to
India? Without it, it can India truly
influence global decisions or remain a
passive participant in a system shaped
by others. Let me explain what veto
power is. In the United in the United
Nations, veto power means you have the
five permanent members of the UN
Security Council and there's a decision
being made and let's say four of them
are in favor of the of the decision but
the fifth one says it's against my my
interest so I will veto it. That means
that even if just one member says no,
that thing can't go forward. That's a
veto power. Okay. Now India obviously is
not a permanent member. India doesn't
have the veto power. The question is how
does India get the veto power? Because
that can make you truly influential. You
can truly influence global decisions.
Otherwise you are a less active
participant. Not a part passive
participant but a less active
participant. So the question is how does
one acquire the veto power? One acquires
the veto power my friends by becoming so
powerful that even without the UN
security council veto power through your
actions in the world you can veto things
for that you need a tremendous economic
might and you also need military might
that can stop things in the world by
gaining real world veto power of
actually stopping things from happening
in the world
then you will get actual the United
Nations veto power because then it makes
it will make sense for them to give it
to you. Otherwise, you could provoke a
big conflict. So, that's how you get
veto power. Okay, I'm going to do this
for another 10 15 minutes and then we
will be done. Let me take the remaining
questions. Villiant Prince says given
AI's rapid rise, I believe the best
salary to work our jobs in 10 years will
be in AI, quantitative trading, trading,
bioinformatives, and international
property uh intellectual property law.
Am I being too harsh for raising my
child this way, fearing a hyperco
competitive future? No. No, you're not
being too harsh raising a child this
way. You are being uh practical. You
have some understanding of the way of
the direction the world is going in. The
future is not going to be hyper
competitive, but it's going to exclude a
lot of people. A lot of people are going
to be left by left on the way side.
those who don't
adopt the the the technology the AI
technology so the whole world is going
to be AI enabled AI will be embedded in
everything eventually
so you have to be an early adopter and
you have to embrace AI wholesale in
everything you do if you do that you
won't first of all be left behind
secondly you'll be at the forefront of
whatever happens so whatever Whatever
work, whatever business you're in,
whatever industry you're in today,
whatever work you do, if you fi can find
a way to incorporate AI into your
workflow, into your processes, into your
business, into your SOPs, etc. If you
can make AI an integral part of that,
and if you stay ab breast of what's
happening in AI, of all the latest
developments, then you will be
unstoppable. So, what you're saying
makes sense. Yeah. the best works the
best jobs in 10 years will be all AI
dominated jobs whatever industry
whatever domain they are in it's it's
going to be deeply connected
interconnected with AI so you've got to
raise your kids that way the future is
going to be exactly like that and those
who don't adopt AI today well it'll be
too late for them to adopt it later
says I saw a podcast where the host
claimed Aria was targeted by Hindus in
the past pundits destroyed his folks due
to his scientific thinking.
What can I say? This is nonsense.
Nonsense. Anybody can do a podcast
today, right? This is a democratic
world. All you need is a is a cell phone
and we can do a podcast. So, there's so
much noise today. The signal to noise
ratio is completely skewed and anybody
can come and make any claim. So, my
question to you is sir, why are you
wasting your time watching the podcasts?
Please don't.
Okay. The scrummer says, "Reports say
that China is faking population numbers.
What's my view? I have no view about
this. How do I know what's really
happening in China? I'll go by the
official reports because I have no other
way of knowing what's happening.
There's always a possibility that
something is being exaggerated or or
built up or cut down, you know,
artificially. But eventually the truth
comes out over time. So, we'll see.
Dr. Patnik says after the creation of
Bangladesh and the surrender of 93,000
troops for Pakistan why didn't we take
Rangpur to solve chicken neck issue and
chhattogram for seaw route after to the
to the far east of India even after we
won that's a question the the the
leaders of that time will have to answer
but they are not around to answer it
today I have no idea why I think u we
are just too generous our leaders have
shown historically they have shown that
they are just too generous they don't
know what to do with a victory they
don't have the killer instinct perhaps
Or maybe there are certain other
coercive forces involved that we are not
aware of. But whatever it is, it it is
it was a golden opportunity. We had won
the military victory. We could have done
whatever we wanted with the territory we
had captured.
And um yeah, we ended up the way we are
today. It's it's it doesn't make any
sense whatsoever. The world doesn't take
India seriously for to a large extent
because of these things that India even
after it wins it it fritters away all
the advantage
Prashant says reverse discrim
reverse discrimination lawsuits in US
workforce thoughts
reverse discrimination what is reverse
discrimination so discrimination means
the white people are targeting black
people and discriminating against black
people so reverse discrimination means
that white people are now claiming that
there's too much discrimination against
whites
Well,
uh, yeah. So, the majority is being
targeted by the minorities and being
discriminated against by the so-called
minorities. Well, that's that's that's
going to be a feature of US society, a
society where you have such
fragmentation and such infighting and so
on. Yeah, it's going to be an increasing
more and more visible feature of US
society. What can I say? It's it's sad
that the US has brought itself down to
this level. was once the greatest
country in the world until the 1950s and
1960s and then the the
decline started and it's still
declining. I don't know where it where
it ends really.
Sally says thoughts saw recent
exploration of duara outcome. I haven't
seen any any news any reports about it.
Whatever is happening is pretty gradual
in
incremental work. No, no, no big
discovery has come out of duara. So I
I'm not aware of any any outcome
whatsoever. But at least something is
being done. So I'm I'm happy to see
that. Yati says, "If we had our own
Indian judiciary system at the time of
the Mahabharat, how would the Supreme
Court have solved the conflict between
the Pandavas and the Koravas?" I'm so
glad we did not have this judiciary
system during the time of the Mahabarat.
We had our own judiciary, our own form
of solving disputes
which was typically see at that time
there were two kingdoms, right? A
judicial system can exist only inside a
kingdom. At that time Bharat Wash was
not under a single emperor
like it was during the time of Chandra
Gupta Mori or Ashok or Kaneshka or the
Gupta emperors etc. When you have a
whole subcontinent unified under a
single emperor and single empire then
you have a unified
judicial system whatever form it takes.
But during the Mahabharat time we did
not have a single empire. We had two
sets of cousins fighting each other and
they had two separate kingdoms.
So there would be no judicial system on
top of that right obviously it doesn't
make any sense think about it think
critically my friends when you have two
let's say India and Pakistan are
fighting do you think there will be a
common judiciary that will tell India
and Pakistan what to do
if let's say China and Japan are
fighting do you think there will be some
common judiciary over China China and
Japan who will tell them what to do
there's no such thing
similarly
when the korovas and the pandas are
fighting each other and they were in
conflict There was no common judiciary
and I'm glad there was none. What
happened was the right thing. It had to
be it had to be solved the way it was
solved.
Zishan says, "Was the US
was the US Army 250th parade
disappointing? Does it does this mean
the US military is weaker than the world
thought?" It doesn't mean the US
military is weak. First of all, was it
disappointing? It was very embarrassing.
It was very half-hearted.
uh it was not serious and so on. It was
very yeah embarrassing for the US. Does
it mean the US military is weaker than
the world thought? Look,
the quality of a military is not to be
gorged from the precision of its parade.
Even a bunch of non-military people can
be made to can be drilled to parade like
the like the North Korean military. If
you force them to parade every day under
a proper drill surgeon for six months,
they'll turn out superb. It doesn't mean
they can fight.
So the quality of a military is not to
be judged from the quality of their
parade turnouts. Okay? The US military
is frighteningly powerful.
Way more powerful than people can
imagine. So yeah, it was definitely
disappointing, embarrassing, but it has
no bearing on the quality of the US
military. It probably was kind of a snub
for Trump. Actually, Trump is not these
aren't good days for Trump, you know,
not good days for him.
Okay. Rahul says, "What's my take on
synthetic meats and the current state of
such food technology?" I think synthetic
meats are a very dangerous thing. I
don't know what is being put in that. Um
and uh it's definitely unnatural
and if people really want to eat meat
then eat actual meat and do it do it
ethically and as cruelty-free as
possible but synthetic meats I think
there could be artificial and dangerous
components in that. So I would say steer
clear of synthetic meats.
Ammer Singh says, "What if India in the
future uses AI and quantum computers to
develop jet engines at the earliest?"
Well, the jet engine problem is not an a
problem that will be solved with AI or
quantum computing. It's a methological
problem. It's a material science
problem. Of course, you can
you can design various kinds of
materials and compounds
etc. and and alloys possibly using uh
artificial intelligence. But then
designing them in a computer simulation
or or having an AI design such things is
very different from actually producing
them, right? Because for that you need
certain kinds of furnaces and things
which require certain kinds of
technologies. How do you grow a single c
crystal blade with multiple holes in it
for cooling and all that? That AI is not
enough for that, right? Otherwise, I
could do it with AI, but I need the
machines and all that. The machines need
machines that make them also. So, it's
it's a different kind of problem. Uh, of
course, we can certainly leverage AI and
uh to the to the fullest extent possible
if if uh that is on the cards, but um at
the end of the day, it will have to be
manufactured in the physical world and
that is that is a whole different issue.
Um Vishal, thank you very much sir.
Hardik Jooshi says why is Europe failing
as a concept? Because it's an artificial
concept. My dear friends, Europe is an
artificial concept. I mean oh we haven't
opened the map today. Let's open the
map. Let's open the map. Europe is a
racist concept. It's a fake concept.
It's an artificial concept. Look at this
continent.
It's one single continent and a tiny
portion of that is what they call Europe
and it is attached to the rest of the
continent Eurasia.
This concept that Europe is a is an is a
separate entity is completely artificial
and completely fake.
It's a small component of Eurasia. The
real powers in Eurasia are Russia,
China, India.
And Europe was propped up by the US for
about 70 80 years as a as a geopolitical
experiment. US the US was the dominant
power in Western Europe. It has created
this these these alliances the EU and
NATO. One is economic, one is military
alliance.
Uh but historically if you see the
history of Europe, they have always been
fighting each other, constant warfare
against each other with a dominating
power which was the Vatican.
But constantly fighting each other,
constant warfare, constant strife,
constant um sectarian strife, constant
ethnic strife, constant linguistic
strife, constant strife.
That's what history, the history of
Europe actually is. You have to read
history, study history for that. So
Europe is simply reverting to its
natural state now that the the the US is
showing less interest and the US is
destabilizing Europe by forcing illegal
im immigration into into Europe with the
aim of uh reconfiguring the demography
of Europe. So
so the the reasons are the the
benevolent hand of the US which is on
top of everything right and the economy
is dropping. Well why does an economy
drop? Tell me why does an economy
decline? The question you to ask
yourself is what drives an economy? And
the very simple answer is that it is
energy that drives an economy. For an
economy to thrive, you need a you need
copious amounts of cheap energy. And
when that when that tap dries out, well,
your economy will go into a recession.
Simple.
Spade says, "Sar, what do you think the
government can do about the judiciary?
They have shown signs of corruption and
even act against India's national
interest at times. Well, I am not a
judicial expert. I have no idea about
the judiciary. I would say that the
government will have to take some proper
action. They've tried taking action in
the past with the uh there was some some
constitutional amendment they had done
but the judiciary threw that out. So I
think the government will have to find
some other way of of reforming the
judiciary because in a democracy if you
want to call yourself a democracy the
judiciary has to come firmly under the
ambit of the will of the people. It
cannot be beyond the ambit of the will
of the people. I think that's how a
democracy is defined and how it works.
So I think it is up to the elected
government of of the people of India to
take the right action whatever the most
appropriate form of action would be but
it's up to them and they have to do it.
They they've got to do it.
Mr. Dot, thank you very much sir. Thank
you.
Dr. Aritwick says why is the US the
number one ally of a small country
Israel? Well,
we don't know.
Uh maybe they love Israel very much.
Maybe they love Judeo-Christian culture
very much and Judaism is the root of
Christianity. Maybe that's the reason or
maybe there could be some other reason
possibly.
Tanmay says your views on Chhatrapati
Shabaji Maharaj and how is great life
ended why people can't accept many bad
things have happened in the past they
just deny. Well, I haven't studied the
life and history of of the Marata Empire
and their various great warrior kings.
So, I don't know the life history of
Chhatraati Shambad Tama Maharaj in
detail, but obviously his life ended uh
with great cruelty done by Orurange to
him with with a great amount of pain and
torture and it is uh
it it it makes your blood boil obviously
right now. Was a great warrior, great
man. And yeah what what this this this
invader this occupier of India did to
him was was beyond brutal.
Uh so I don't know why people can't
accept that bad things have happened in
the past. They have happened in the past
and uh we need to ensure that those are
taught to us and we ensure that that
such things don't happen again in the
future.
Rashi Kudin says Iran claims
it has weapons that are better than
nuclear weapons. What are my thoughts?
Well, if I ask myself what weapons can
be better than nuclear weapons, the
answer kind of frightens me. Okay,
weapons that are more dangerous than
nuclear weapons could be either chemical
or biological weapons which will have
devastating effects of various kinds
that are different from the devastation
that is caused by a nuclear weapon. Now,
I don't know if that's what they mean by
that. Okay, Iran, does it mean that they
are claiming they have nuclear they have
chemical or biological weapons? I don't
know if it means that. So, I don't know.
First of all, I don't even know if they
have claimed this. Secondly, if they
have claimed this, I don't know what it
means. So, my my answer is I have no
idea what it means. Uh I can't think of
anything else beyond chemical and
biological that that is carrier than
nuclear.
Yeah, of course you can have hypersonic
missiles and you can saturate strike a
city which can have the same effect as a
nuclear weapon but for that you need a
100 hypersonic missiles
but when it comes to nukes you just need
one. So I don't know what's what's
better or more dangerous than nuclear.
Not sure. Sharma says P and Oak said
that Rome was named after Lord Ram and
Rahan Ravena was named after Raan and
they worshiped Hindu gods in Europe.
Well, PNO has made all kinds of claims
and he has also made speeious claims
like some kind of book some kind of
fictitious poem written about written
about
King Vikram Madhate by the Arabs of
which there is no evidence at all. So PN
Oak is not regarded as a as as a
reliable historical source. That's what
I need to caution you all about. Okay,
he has made all kinds of claims. Much of
these claims are there's no evidence for
them.
Spade says the greatest Hindu king in
recorded history is Vikramity right his
kingdom reached Rossia right could you
share some facts about him I don't know
any facts about him he's regarded as a
mythical legendary king which I am sure
is incorrect but we don't have any hard
evidence about his kingdom his life and
so on so forth mostly because our
historians and archaeologists have not
done the right have not put in enough
effort to to find out the truth they
just content to dismiss him as a
legendary king. So I don't know what the
deal is. Kingdom reached Russia. I'm not
sure about that. Uh what facts? I don't
know the facts. Sorry. Mr. Dot says,
"Will the Indian cities infrastructure
improve and how? Indian cities can have
their infrastructure improve drastically
if India cracks down on corruption."
That's the simple answer I can give you.
We can have tremendous cities in the in
the world in in the country. Tremendous
worldass cities. tremendous. We can have
them in India. Big beautiful cities. But
only if we crack down on corruption.
We need a war on corruption. If if we do
that, the cities will become completely
transformed in India. Completely
transformed. There'll be no more slums
full of Rohingya and Bangladeshes and
cookies and Pakistanis.
There'll be no open sewers if they still
exist. There'll be no floods every time
there's a 5minute rainfall. Everything
will change if we crack down on
corruption. So where is India's war on
corruption when it happens things will
change. Adity Pande thank you very much
sir Aditi G. Thank you. Babyface says
what are the chances of Air India crash
being a sabotage? Uh PS geost strategy
episodes are fantastic. Thank you sir. I
appreciate it. I am glad you like those.
What are the chances of Air India crash
being a sabotage? See this is an ongoing
investigation. I would not want to make
any statements about this right now.
I clearly have said this I I made I mean
I did a segment on this during one of my
geost strategy episodes in which I said
that this is most likely it looks like
it's most likely a simultaneous dual
engine failure. Now I have some kind of
understanding uh of of um aviation. I am
by no means a professional but I have um
some understanding because of my
lifelong interest in it. So, it looks
like this was a simultaneous dual engine
failure, which is incredibly rare and
doesn't make any sense for this to
happen. And now it looks like there's
more evidence coming out that kind of
indicates it's a simultaneous dual
engine failure. Now, what can cause
that? Bird strikes. Doesn't look like
there was any bird strike. What else?
Fuel contamination. Oh, that's very
dangerous and very fishy. So, I don't
know at this point in time what it was.
I think the government needs to do a
proper investigation. The the cockpit
flight recorder needs to be analyzed.
the cockpit, voice recorder, the flight,
the black box, all of that needs to be
analyzed. The actual physical remains of
the aircraft and whatever else need to
be analyzed and we need to find out what
happened. We need to get to the bottom
of this. Until this happens, I would
rather not comment about whether this
could be a sabotage or not. I think at
this point in time, I think every
possibility is is has to be taken
seriously. That's all I'll say.
Geopolitical Dubai says, "What are my
thoughts on Abij Ayatra? I think he's a
fantastic guy. Very very nice guy.
uh very intelligent, very bright, uh
very entertaining, very funny, very well
read, very scholarly and so on.
Adity Pande says, "Recommend books
Saty. Recommend books and sources to
prove Satya. Read the book by Dr. Binaki
Jan about Sati. That's the only book you
need. Go to amazon.com and okay, let me
let me spoon feed you. Go to amazon.com
or flipkart.com or whatever your
favorite website is and type this
minakshi jen sati with spaces in
between. Buy that book. Read it. That's
the book you need. All right.
All right.
[Laughter]
Muhammad Vishnu from Indonesia.
Definitely a viewer of mine.
Okay. Muhammad Vishnu says, "Can India
become US sanctioned proof?" Not anytime
soon. Not anytime soon because we are
connected to the global economy which is
dominated by the US. The global economy
is is is denominated in the US dollar.
It's the global reserve currency. Every
all most transactions happen in in that
currency. and all the entire global
financial system that we are connected
to the swift system and so on so forth
everything it's all dominated by the US
all the supply chains that we have that
bring in stuff to India are dominated by
the US so not anytime soon we're not
going to be sanctions proof anytime soon
it'll take time minimum 20 30 years who
knows
says if Iran falls like Syria will the
will the whole of West Asia be a US
fifdom with Turkey and greater Israel as
its lege lords. Will they then divorce
Israel? Will US gobble up the rimland
and push it further till they whatever?
Well, you bring out Mr. Mackinder and
his theory. Well, a long time ago in in
an episode of the Indian interest, I
believe I had spoken about the heartland
rimland theory of of Machinda, right?
and uh
and and it says that the heartland of
Asia is is the historical USSR which is
presently Russia and parts of China,
Mongolia etc. and that's where all the
resources are and whoever dominates the
heartland dominates the world island and
rimland nations like India are not in a
position to dominate and so on and so
forth that's a theory right so if Iran
falls like Syria definitely the whole of
West Asia will become a US thief uh
Israel will be the major le lord in the
region Turkey will not be very pleased
with this but Turkey will try and make
the best of what it can Turkey is an
ever grasping country um
who will divorce Israel the US the US
will never divorce Israel. Turkey Turkey
has a lovehate relationship with Israel
that will continue. Uh if if Iran falls,
will the US gobble up the rimland? Well,
a large part of the rimland goes to the
US if the US can take over Iran and then
they would like to make further inroads
into the Caucasus region into the Middle
East region is done already. The Central
Asia also you can push from from Iran
and so on. So yeah, it'll be a great
great decisive uh um victory of sorts
for the US but not the the final
victory. The final victory means you get
the heartland and that that will be a
different longer term project.
Knowledge camp. Thank you very much sir
or ma'am. Thank you so much. Uh NTN88
said that says why are people still
obsessed with oil? Haven't we moved on?
Minerals is the new oil hype was years
ago. Well, if you look at the world,
look at transportation, look at
everything. Look at the major sources of
energy. It's all oil. It's all fossil
fuels. We're trying to move to lithium.
We're trying to move to other exotic
sources and and and green energy and so
on so forth, but the vast majority of
energy still comes from fossil fuels and
oil. Can you have an F-35 flying with
only lithium?
Can you have a Boeing 747 or an Airbus
380 flying on lithium?
Can you have a super tanker transporting
uh thousand tons of of goods from one
continent to another on lithium? It's
all still based on fossil fuels. Then
people aren't obsessed with oil. People
are practical and pragmatic and
realistic.
Most of the world's energy resources are
still based on fossil fuels, mainly oil.
Why Jati Vari says why is India building
ports and sat sats ports and sats in the
Indian Ocean region in Africa. If you if
you invest in ports you get to control
those ports which means that you can
control various spokes and hubs in the
various supply chains. So that's an
advantage that you have. Imagine if
China controls all the ports then what
will you do? Then you'll be at their
mercy. They can cut things off for you.
But if you control ports like like for
example the Adani group controls the
Hifa port in Israel well that's a great
advantage for us and so on. So we need
to build ports. We need to build our own
infra infrastructure in the region in
Africa East Africa in the Indian Ocean
region and so on so forth. We need to
have our own listening stations. We need
to have our own radar stations possibly
dual use military bases and so on so
forth. That's in infra in infrastructure
you own and you operate. So it's it's an
advantage for you. Uh NLE Shivas. Thank
you very much sir for becoming a member.
Thank you. Geopolitical dubet thank you
so much.
Rush good. Thank you very much. Thank
you very much sir. Uh PLTP says
why people allow politicians after
independence to keep doing blunders? Why
the 90% 97% who voted to make Pakistan
under Sharia alo law were allowed to
stay in India? First of all the people
had no say. See you you have to
understand how political power works.
Political power like Maung said flows
from the barrel of a gun. It also flows
from the the latte that that the
policeman holds.
People had no say in what politicians
could or could not do. The politicians
controlled everything. They controlled
the means of violence. They controlled
the means of everything else. That's how
they controlled the country. And they
kept on doing blunder after blunder
because the people had no choice. What
would the people have done? Do you
remember in the 1960s or something uh
5,000 Hindu sadhus went to the Lok Sabha
went to parliament to demonstrate
against cows slaughter. What happened to
them? They were shot.
Are you aware of that? The massacre of
Hindu sados outside parliament house
sometime in the 1950s.
They tried to do something about about
this state of our country. What
happened? They were massacred.
So that's how the world works
and so so on so forth about the 97
person who wanted to uh make Pakistan
and they stayed in India. Well yeah
Pandit says
Jews were never persecuted in India.
Well
I have no idea what you're writing.
Welcome
every religion but Israel is still
converting
tribals and same with China. Will our
ideology be a cost paid by Indians?
Yeah, we will have to take care of our
national interests. Okay, my point is
what I've been saying don't consider
anybody to be your en enemy but don't
consider any anyone to be your
unconditional friend. Everybody has
their interest and some of the interest
will go against your interests. So be
careful and don't cry that we never hurt
you but you are hurting us. No, be
practical. Be realistic. The world is
like this. So we have to take care of
our interest. Our government is supposed
to take care of our interests. If it's
not doing it, please call them out.
Okay. Slayer says, "Should I join the
mafia? Baloo the gangster?" Well, if
Balu the gangster appeals to you, please
join his Baloo the Gangster mafia.
I'm just kidding. Okay. Prattab says is
Iran's fall is not our interests.
Why are we for Israel? I am I have never
said that Iran's fall is in our
interest. So I agree with you and you
what you say is is make sense. Iran's
fall is not in our interest. We have
nothing against Israel but Iran should
not fall otherwise it's terrible for us.
It's a disaster for us if there's a
regime change in Thran. Secret
billionaire says how would Chanaka seize
power in today's India if he existed
today and wanted to run India his way
what would it be his strategy sir
Chanaka's strategy would not be a regime
change operation like he did against the
Nanda Empire Chanaki strategy would be
to win elections and once you win the
election and become reach the top
position you ensure you never leave that
would be his strategy that is the way of
Chanaka don't fight the system use the
system to get what you want and then
change the system if you can and I
assure you Chanaka can. Chanaka is way
greater than anybody who stands as a
politician in India today.
Aigan says you said earlier that the
presidential system of government is
better for India but parliamentary
government is part of basic structure of
constitution. Can the government change
it? I'm a big fan of memory power. My
memory power is just okay. Anyhow, um
parliamentary government is part of the
basic structure of the constitution. Can
the government change it? I think only a
constitutional expert can answer this
question. I think it's very difficult
actually from whatever I understand for
the government to change the so-called
basic structure of the constitution. I'm
not even sure what this basic structure
of the constitution is.
The constitution is a man-made document.
It's supposed to be a living document
that changes over time. and it doesn't
we we are under no obligation to keep on
obeying a document that was written
about 80 years ago and not even ratified
by the people of India. So I'm sure when
whenever there's a politician or a
leader with sufficient willpower and
fortitude the change will happen. But
yeah, we're going to have to pray for
that person to appear.
Hersh says, "Ha, thank you first of all
uh please tell your views on
spirituality on God and also if you
follow and practice any kind of
spiritual practice in your daily life as
well. Look, first of all, first of all,
I thank you for your contribution. But I
am not taking questions about anything
except for geopolitics, history or
current affairs. But my views on
spirituality, I think it's up to you
what you want to what kind of life you
want to live, what kind of god you want
to worship, god, gods, whatever. I am a
believer.
I I am obviously
um what do what what can I say? My
spirituality practice I don't have any
spirituality practice as such uh I have
the greatest of respect and reverance
for our ancestral traditions our dharmic
traditions. So if I have any
spirituality it is that the utmost
utmost respect and reverance for our
ancestral spiritual traditions our
culture our civilizational
civilizational path the dharmic path and
all the gods and goddesses come with
that
keshi says will you join my conquest if
I become a billionaire by 25 also do you
have a will to come out of content
creation and join the real cause you
become a billionaire I'm I'm with you
Absolutely.
Uh Ankita says, "I have this phob phobia
of lagging behind when it comes to AI.
Please say something for me your
suggestions." If you don't want to lag
behind when it comes to AI, you will
have to embrace AI in whatever
profession or or whatever it is that you
do. Um
which means that let's say you are
um what hypothetical
profession can I find? Let's say you are
a chartered accountant
and you have to do a lot of manual
calculations and all for all your
clients. Well, you could have what you
do is you you you'll have to learn a
little bit of how how software
development is done. You need to
understand the flow. You need to have a
requirements document. Then a design
document. Then you need to have uh code.
Then you need to have unit testing and
integration testing, user acceptance
testing in case of existing applications
and all. Then you need to create if you
are a CA,
you get your hands on something called
cursor. Then you need learn how to talk
with AI, how to communicate with AI. You
can also get clone code if you want
inside cursor. And then you create an
application that does all of your
calculations, all of your analysis,
everything for you. And you just have to
input the documents and it'll it'll give
you everything. Then you can obviously
supervise what it does, double check
what it does. But it really really
really acts as a force multiplier for
you. So then instead of having 20
employees, you can just have 20 AI
employees and and spend a fraction of
the cost. That sort of thing. So what
you have to do if you are fearful of AI,
you're afraid possibly because you don't
understand it. See what do we fear in in
the world? We fear darkness. Why? Why do
we fear darkness? Because darkness is
the unknown.
Similarly, when it comes to various
technologies, we fear them because we
don't understand them. So, you have to
take the time. You you to invest the
time and the effort to learn things.
Learn something that may be very new to
you, something you've never experienced
before, but you have to take the time to
learn it. And then you have to take the
time to incorporate it into whatever
your profession is. That's what you do.
So without knowing what exactly it is
that you do, it's very hard for me to
give specific details, but I give the
example of a CA. You can you can replace
all your employees with AI, AI systems,
AI agents if you know how to use AI. So
learn how to use AI and you get all
these courses online. You know, you can
spend a few few hours every week over
the next year and try stuff, try and do
new things and you'll learn. So that's
what I can say. learn. You have to learn
it. You have to embrace it. It's It's
going to be uncomfortable. It's going to
be difficult. It may be terrifying, but
don't stop. Do it. All right. All the
best everybody.
Goind says the U Iran asks the US to
stop war with Israel. What will be the
result of this? Do you think Iran will
agree to stop enriching uranium for
nuclear weapons or is this a delaying
tactic for testing a nuke? I think Iran
if it has any sense will enrich
sufficient uranium to at least be a
threshold state
because otherwise you have an
existential threat. Right? Asking the US
to stop the war will have will serve no
purpose. Israel will do what Israel
wants and the US will support Israel. So
I I don't think Iran will agree to stop
enriching uranium. It doesn't make sense
for them to stop doing that. They will
have to become a threshold state. I'm
not sure if they will test nuclear
weapons. I think there's a 35%
probability they will do it in the next
one year which is the which is not a
very high probability. It's not very low
either. It depends on various factors on
how their threat perception is on v on
whether is Israel continues targeting
Iran and so on so forth.
So I think it makes sense for Iran to
not stop enriching uranium. I think it
makes sense for them to have a stockpile
of at least 10 warheads worth of 90%
plus enriched uranium which is weapons
grade uranium. That's what I think Iran
Iran will have to do. I'm not
recommending that. I'm just saying that
it makes sense for a nation in their
position in their circumstances to do
that.
AJ Sharma says are BSF, ASI, DRDO
actually doing anything meaningful or
just running on legacy budget in
bureaucracy? There's a mixture of both I
would say the ASI uh I have said that as
the ASI should be disbanded and a new
professional organization needs to be
created because look even there may be a
lot of good people also possibly in the
ASI at least some may be good but
overall the hierarchy in the bureaucracy
is such that things won't be allowed to
change I'm sure there are good people I
think there are good people fantastic
people in every organization but overall
the system the architecture, the
superstructure, the system, the
bureaucracy, all of that is such that
things don't change and a lot of the old
practices that have been going on
forever which are not necessarily great
will continue.
So that is something every system faces.
Even good systems eventually become slow
and oified. So the the point is that you
have to keep them nimble, keep them
agile, keep on trimming the fat and keep
on staffing them with great people and
whenever required reforms need to be
done. So I think everybody faces this.
I'm sure the BSF may possibly face it.
I'm sure the ASI definitely faces it.
DRDO also needs a lot of reforms.
Please, please trust me. DRDO needs a
lot of reforms. So yeah, that's the
deal.
Okay, I am not taking questions about
religion and all these matters. Okay,
this is not the place for that.
Uh, Susant says, I once saw a sign
driving in Los Angeles called Little
Bangladesh. Any views? Kind of curious
on why
must be a bunch of Bangladeshes who
lived there and they felt like
recreating their home. I mean, you have
little China, you have China towns in
the west, right?
Um
I'm not sure if you have little Indas.
Of of course if you go to New Jersey,
there's more than a little India there.
So why not have the Bangladeshes also
create their own little corner of the
world in in Los Angeles.
You know people people that's human
nature that you want to congregate
together with the people who who are
similar to you who's who speak the same
language who look like you who have a
common background cultural um etc
historical ethnic background you want to
congregate together birds of a feather
like to flock together right so I think
if you have sufficient enough number of
Bangladeshes then they may want to
create a small part of the
where it feels like home. So maybe
that's why it is. I I haven't seen this
little Bangladesh myself but in case
it's there maybe that's the reason why
it's there.
Udb says Jhen Jar thank you. Well thank
you so much yourself sir Udb g. Okay her
sha says are gujus not of warrior class
expect chalukas who are ancient kings of
Gujarat why don't they contribute in the
Indian Indian army? This is such
nonsense. This is such nonsense. If you
look at the per capita contribution to
the Indian army from every state, I'm
not going to go and dig up that right
now. If you do that, all you have to do
is look at the per capita contribution.
How many people from a state uh become
join the Indian armed forces out of
every one lakh people in the population?
I'm sure the statistics exist and you'll
be surprised if you see them. So I don't
know why we like to fight each other in
this country and point fingers at each
other. Oh this state is bad, that state
is bad. These people are are not
contributing enough. These people are
taking too much. This is a problem in
this country that is causing us to keep
fighting each other. And this is a prime
example of that.
So and so state is not a warrior class.
They don't contribute to the Indian
army. Come on man. Come on. Is this all
you will do in your life? Pathetic.
Really?
Rudai says thank you. Okay, thank you so
much. Thank you so much. I really
appreciate your kind words and your
contribution.
Uh Ragu Nandan Jah Jahir says who would
succeed Prime Minister Modi and Hill
will he she be able to create the same
level of impact? What should be the what
should the BJP do to make sure we build
on top of what Mr. the Modi government
has already done or started? Well, the
most crucial period in a nation's
history
is transition periods,
succession.
You have to ensure the success
succession goes right. Which means that
the transfer of power has to happen to
the right person otherwise all the good
work done by the previous ruler or the
previous leader will be wasted if the
wrong kind of person comes to power. So
that's very important. Now who will
succeed Mr. Modi etc. I have no idea at
this point in time. I think it's still a
few years in the future but not very far
in the future possibly. Possibly. Okay.
I don't know. Possibly. So I think the
what the BJP needs to do in case the BJP
wants to stay in power next time. Yeah.
It needs to ensure that there is
meritocracy and the most the the the
leaders grassroots leaders and middle
run leaders who perform the best and who
have the most potential they should be
promoted. And at the end of the day the
best among those should be the next
eventual successor to Mr. Modi whenever
that happens. That's what need to needs
to be done. Tanmay Pant says why no
science revolution in the Mughal Empire
like the UK the 7th century mogul
culprit has the wasted resources in
luxury.
Have you seen a science revolution among
the Turks? The Moguls were Turks right?
Have you seen a scientific revolution in
Turkey during the 17th century 16th
century? There was no such thing.
After the reign of Sullean the
Magnificent, everything went slowly
gradually downhill for Turkey. They did
not have the culture of of scientific
excellence, of scientific inquiry. They
didn't not have that, right?
And the same goes for the Turks who who
occupied India, the so-called Mughal
Empire. They also did not have any of
that.
Um the Persians at least had some of
this. The Persians uh the Persians tried
the the Turks h nothing.
Pranay Kumar says is it possible to
transport payload by quantum mechanics?
They've been
everything all transportation is at the
end of the day quantum mechanical. Why
is there friction between the wheels of
a vehicle in the in the in the in the in
the road? Because of quantum mechanics.
Why does matter occupy space? Because of
Powi's exclusion principle. All of all
of everything, all of reality is quantum
mechanical. If you go deep deep down, so
beyond that, I'm not sure what quantum
mechanical technologies you want to
transport payloads. But even chemistry,
chemical rockets, well, it's these
chemical reactions are quantum
mechanical in nature, aren't they? Nil
says
it's clear that there's no proof of
fifth
dimension. Then why is string theories
so popular? String theories are popular.
It's like a real thing.
It's because a small number of people
have have captured the academic
institutions, the the physics
departments in the United States. I call
them the string theory mafia. They have
captured everything. And today in the
US, if you want to do a PhD in
theoretical physics, nine times out of
10, you would do it in string theory.
And this is a completely futile
endeavor, completely futile exercise.
They've had five, six decades to to find
some breakthrough in physics. They've
done nothing. All they've done is invent
new and new more complicated kinds of
maths which are math which are which are
fun. No question about it. There's no I
have no issue with math. But where's the
where's the physics? Where's the
breakthroughs? There's not a single
testable prediction
made by string theory. So it's because a
small number of people the string theory
of mafia have captured academia and
that's why it is what it is the way it
is. That's why it's so supposedly so
popular.
Virgo Saga, thank you very much, sir.
Thank you.
Genuine beatbox says, "Do you wear full
dress or only suit on top? I only wear
suit on top. I only wear what's
visible."
[Laughter]
Okay. Susant says, "The government
dreams of being a superpower, yet
corruption runs the show. Do they really
think this works or are they pretending
not to notice? Maybe corruption is
something the government hasn't created
but they have inherited the Modi
government did not create the corruption
right corruption exists no question
allegedly everywhere allegedly it is
everywhere and allegedly it runs the
whole country allegedly the whole system
runs on allegedly corruption but did the
Modi government create this or did they
inherited they have inherited it and one
one hears that at least at the very top
level the corruption has been dis has
been wiped out hopefully
That's what one hears hopefully and then
slowly you can bring it down. So one
would like to see a war on corruption at
the coming down downstream also but I'm
sure it's a huge issue allegedly a very
big deep rooted issue allegedly so it's
very hard to fight it maybe it'll take
decades to fight it I don't know what it
is yeah yeah but but I agree with you
Susant that without
eradicating corruption this this all
this nonsense of superpower visha guru
it's all just going to be slogans we're
not going to get near that So from that
perspective you are 100% correct.
GG SSS and this is the last question for
today. So the question is what's the
best way for US citizen OCI to
contribute to the bat to the bharati
national interest? Well I'll tell you
what's the best way become super wealthy
and then invest in bhat in in in in some
sector that is that is crucial for
India's national interest. maybe the
semiconductor sector, maybe defense
manufacturing or something, right? So
something like that you can do if you
are wealthy. So first become super
wealthy, then invest what you can in
Barat in a way that is is great that is
aligned with Barat's national interest.
And if you're not super wealthy, well,
it's not your fault. If you're not super
wealthy, invest in whatever way you can
in something like this. That's what I
would say.
Or you can act as a an official
ambassador of bhat wherever you are and
and you know help the people wherever
you are US in the US understand bat
better
that's another thing you can do to
contribute to bat's national interest so
be creative in whatever way you can
contribute do contribute and I
appreciate the sentiment and do well all
right
okay there's one more question this has
to be the last question. Okay. Spade,
thank you very much, sir. I'll keep
smiling. S
Gorov says, "I'm not able to understand
the glove analogy in physics that you
always give
the glove analogy. You mean quantum
entanglement."
So, let's say you have two gloves. We
know that gloves come in two shapes,
right? Left-handed glove and
right-handed glove. So, I take these two
gloves, brand new. I put them in two
boxes.
I put the two box two different gloves
in two different boxes. One is a
right-handed glove, one is a left-handed
glove. I take one box, I mail it to Shri
Vladimir Putin GI in Moscow. I take the
other box and I mail it to Shri
Shiinping GI in Beijing. Now I have
shuffled the boxes before I mailed them.
So I also don't know which box contains
which glove. Okay. So Moscow and Beijing
are thousands of kilometers apart. Now
Shri Putin will open his box and let's
say he finds a left-handed glove. Then
he will immediately know that Shri
Vladim Shri Shrian Ping has got the
other one the right-handed glove. So
these two gloves they form a single
system. They are interconnected even
though they are far apart. So let's say
I take the the box from Shri Shiinping
and I send it to my friend in the
Andromeda galaxy through a wormhole. So
it travels very fast. So when my friend
in the Andromeda galaxy opens the the
the box and finds a right-handed glove,
he or she or it will know immediately
that whoever is on Earth has got a
left-handed glove. So these two even
these this system of two gloves, even
though it is now disconnected by
millions of light years, billions of
light years, you can still they are
still correlated in some way. So that's
an analogy for quantum entanglement. A
quantum quantum mechanically entangled
system of particles is described by a
single wave function. You can't separate
the two. And yeah, if you know the pro
the the the the state of one of the two
particles, you will know the state of
the other partic other particle
immediately instantaneously no matter
how far it is. That's the deal. I hope
it uh it's hopefully comprehensible.
So with that, we have come to the end of
today's live stream. It's been a very
long day. It's 11:20 p.m. over here. So,
I'm going to end it over here. Thank you
so much for your all your questions and
I will see you in the next live stream
which will happen day after tomorrow.
Thank you so much. Take care. Keep
asking questions. Keep raising your
standards and I'll see you soon. Thank
you. Bye-bye.